<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://agrilive.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://agrilive.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-31T10:47:55-05:00</updated><id>https://agrilive.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wei Ching’s Website</title><subtitle>Reflections, thoughts, and learnings</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My GCP Associate Cloud Engineer exam experience</title><link href="https://agrilive.github.io/blog/gcp/2020/08/30/GCP-Associate-Cloud-Engineer-Exam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My GCP Associate Cloud Engineer exam experience" /><published>2020-08-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://agrilive.github.io/blog/gcp/2020/08/30/GCP-Associate-Cloud-Engineer-Exam</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://agrilive.github.io/blog/gcp/2020/08/30/GCP-Associate-Cloud-Engineer-Exam.html">&lt;p&gt;I was prepared to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Cloud Platform Associate Cloud Engineer (GCP ACE) Exam has been known to be tough. Google does not make the passing score known officially. However, writers on online forums have mentioned that a 75-80% score is needed to pass the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-exam&quot;&gt;The exam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stepped into the test center, I mentally prepared myself for the 50 questions, 2 hour long paper. Alas, we were not allowed to bring in any pen or blank paper. My plan was to note down my thought process on paper so that I can reference it as I review my answers. Thankfully, there was a “Mark this question for review” box under each question. I made use of it until I realised the uncertainty in my answers and require a relook on most of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half time into the exam, I started losing concentration. Water bottles were not allowed into the test center as well. I shut my eyes temporarily for a short break. Took three deep breaths, and continued the exam. Besides being an intellectually challenging exam, it was an endurance test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to complete the test in 1.5 hours. The exam duration was more than sufficient. I checked through all my questions, made some adjustments and submitted the paper before the timer ended. There were some instruction pages after the submission, including the information that the exam results will be validated and confirmed in 7 to 10 days. As I clicked the final exit button, my eyes vaguely saw the words in green: Passed. Before I knew it, my fingers had clicked the mouse and the page was exited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were my eyes cheating me? I couldn’t believe what I saw. I had passed the exam!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-cloud-student-sprint-program&quot;&gt;Google Cloud Student Sprint Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was part of the Google Cloud Student Sprint Program last summer. It was a ten-week long program where we were split into small teams of five students and have a Googler attached to us. Our mentor was an expert in Google Cloud, and we had weekly mentoring sessions together. During these sessions, we went through key concepts, such as networking, and the questions in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.academia.edu/41551326/Official_Google_Cloud_Certified_Associate_Cloud_Engineer_Study_Guide&quot;&gt;Official Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer Study Guide by Dan Sullivan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention, we were given access to two Coursera courses: Architecting with Google Compute Engine specialization and Preparing for the Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer Exam course. These resources gave me foundational knowledge on GCP and its functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given a schedule to complete these courses, and it was rather manageable. Though I was behind schedule for the first month, I felt taken care of. Charlotte and Su Jen, the Googlers in charge of the program, would check in on me. They were very understanding and gave many encouragements. :smiley:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the program, there were workshops and Recruiter Office Hours almost every week. It was amazing! The workshop I found most impactful was the I Am Remarkable workshop. It was an intimate session with less than ten of us and Charlotte. We were given time to reflect and share our reflections. Tips were also given on how to be confident of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it had been an exciting experience. I would definitely recommend it to students, technical and non-technical ones (I come from a non-technical background), especially those who are interested in a career with Google. The Google Swags given were awesome! :heart_eyes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, I relied on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.academia.edu/41551326/Official_Google_Cloud_Certified_Associate_Cloud_Engineer_Study_Guide&quot;&gt;Official Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer Study Guide by Dan Sullivan&lt;/a&gt;. This study guide gives a brief overview of each concept, and contains questions that test your basic understanding of these concepts, such as the file type to deploy an app in the App Engine. However, there are two downfalls to solely relying on this book for preparation. First, some of the information, such as the answers, may be outdated. This was overcame by the knowledge from our mentor who would point to us the relevant online documentations. Second, the type of questions in the book do not appear in the actual exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual exam was very scenario-based. It tested on your ability to distinguish between the various GCP functions and the situations where one function trumps another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be overcome by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.examtopics.com/exams/google/associate-cloud-engineer/&quot;&gt;Exam Topics Database&lt;/a&gt; which contains 159 GCP questions. One of my peers mentioned that she saw about half of her exam questions appearing in t. However, a caveat is the unrealiable answers given. Readers do discuss about the answer options and provide documentation links to back up their claims. I would suggest looking up these documentations to have a better understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I picked up question-answering techniques from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQMsfKRZZviRwqJwNmh1eAWnRMvlrk40x&quot;&gt;AwesomeGCP Practice Exam Q&amp;amp;A playlist&lt;/a&gt;. I found this very relevant when I was taking the exam. Some questions are tricky by nature. Though the answer choices seem to be correct, they might be using the wrong keywords. For example, the word &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pod&lt;/code&gt; is associated with the Google Kubernetes Engine and not the Compute Engine. Besides that, the elimination technique comes in handy and this series of videos teaches us how to make a smart elimination choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-reflections&quot;&gt;My reflections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, there was too much information to memorise. The most important thing was to &lt;em&gt;understand the concepts&lt;/em&gt;. I relied heavily on the Google Cloud documentations (Concepts and How-to Guides). Illustrations were helpful in breaking the concepts down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since everyone had a different set of exam questions, which were centered on different concepts, I didn’t focus on any concepts in particular. My paper was mainly about Networking and IAM. Others were about computing or storage. The IAM quetions I had were similar in nature, asking about whether roles should be assigned to an individual or group. Linking back to the point on understanding the concepts, it was important to recognise that the recommended Google practice is to create a new group (add the individuals to the group) and assign a role to the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to make the best guess on questions that I was unsure of. Thankfully, I passed the exam.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was prepared to fail. The Google Cloud Platform Associate Cloud Engineer (GCP ACE) Exam has been known to be tough. Google does not make the passing score known officially. However, writers on online forums have mentioned that a 75-80% score is needed to pass the exam. The exam As I stepped into the test center, I mentally prepared myself for the 50 questions, 2 hour long paper. Alas, we were not allowed to bring in any pen or blank paper. My plan was to note down my thought process on paper so that I can reference it as I review my answers. Thankfully, there was a “Mark this question for review” box under each question. I made use of it until I realised the uncertainty in my answers and require a relook on most of them. Half time into the exam, I started losing concentration. Water bottles were not allowed into the test center as well. I shut my eyes temporarily for a short break. Took three deep breaths, and continued the exam. Besides being an intellectually challenging exam, it was an endurance test. I managed to complete the test in 1.5 hours. The exam duration was more than sufficient. I checked through all my questions, made some adjustments and submitted the paper before the timer ended. There were some instruction pages after the submission, including the information that the exam results will be validated and confirmed in 7 to 10 days. As I clicked the final exit button, my eyes vaguely saw the words in green: Passed. Before I knew it, my fingers had clicked the mouse and the page was exited. Were my eyes cheating me? I couldn’t believe what I saw. I had passed the exam! Google Cloud Student Sprint Program I was part of the Google Cloud Student Sprint Program last summer. It was a ten-week long program where we were split into small teams of five students and have a Googler attached to us. Our mentor was an expert in Google Cloud, and we had weekly mentoring sessions together. During these sessions, we went through key concepts, such as networking, and the questions in the Official Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer Study Guide by Dan Sullivan. Not to mention, we were given access to two Coursera courses: Architecting with Google Compute Engine specialization and Preparing for the Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer Exam course. These resources gave me foundational knowledge on GCP and its functionalities. We were given a schedule to complete these courses, and it was rather manageable. Though I was behind schedule for the first month, I felt taken care of. Charlotte and Su Jen, the Googlers in charge of the program, would check in on me. They were very understanding and gave many encouragements. :smiley: Throughout the program, there were workshops and Recruiter Office Hours almost every week. It was amazing! The workshop I found most impactful was the I Am Remarkable workshop. It was an intimate session with less than ten of us and Charlotte. We were given time to reflect and share our reflections. Tips were also given on how to be confident of ourselves. Overall, it had been an exciting experience. I would definitely recommend it to students, technical and non-technical ones (I come from a non-technical background), especially those who are interested in a career with Google. The Google Swags given were awesome! :heart_eyes: Resources As mentioned earlier, I relied on the Official Google Cloud Certified Associate Cloud Engineer Study Guide by Dan Sullivan. This study guide gives a brief overview of each concept, and contains questions that test your basic understanding of these concepts, such as the file type to deploy an app in the App Engine. However, there are two downfalls to solely relying on this book for preparation. First, some of the information, such as the answers, may be outdated. This was overcame by the knowledge from our mentor who would point to us the relevant online documentations. Second, the type of questions in the book do not appear in the actual exam. The actual exam was very scenario-based. It tested on your ability to distinguish between the various GCP functions and the situations where one function trumps another. This might be overcome by the Exam Topics Database which contains 159 GCP questions. One of my peers mentioned that she saw about half of her exam questions appearing in t. However, a caveat is the unrealiable answers given. Readers do discuss about the answer options and provide documentation links to back up their claims. I would suggest looking up these documentations to have a better understanding. In addition, I picked up question-answering techniques from the AwesomeGCP Practice Exam Q&amp;amp;A playlist. I found this very relevant when I was taking the exam. Some questions are tricky by nature. Though the answer choices seem to be correct, they might be using the wrong keywords. For example, the word pod is associated with the Google Kubernetes Engine and not the Compute Engine. Besides that, the elimination technique comes in handy and this series of videos teaches us how to make a smart elimination choice. My reflections Honestly, there was too much information to memorise. The most important thing was to understand the concepts. I relied heavily on the Google Cloud documentations (Concepts and How-to Guides). Illustrations were helpful in breaking the concepts down. Since everyone had a different set of exam questions, which were centered on different concepts, I didn’t focus on any concepts in particular. My paper was mainly about Networking and IAM. Others were about computing or storage. The IAM quetions I had were similar in nature, asking about whether roles should be assigned to an individual or group. Linking back to the point on understanding the concepts, it was important to recognise that the recommended Google practice is to create a new group (add the individuals to the group) and assign a role to the group. I tried to make the best guess on questions that I was unsure of. Thankfully, I passed the exam.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I started my Data Science journey</title><link href="https://agrilive.github.io/blog/data%20science/career/2020/05/24/Social-Science-to-Data-Science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I started my Data Science journey" /><published>2020-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://agrilive.github.io/blog/data%20science/career/2020/05/24/Social-Science-to-Data-Science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://agrilive.github.io/blog/data%20science/career/2020/05/24/Social-Science-to-Data-Science.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m an incoming final-year Politics, Law and Economics (PLE) major student. Never have I thought of going into the tech sector before my university days. In fact, when I started learning Python 1.5 years ago, I told myself I am not going to touch it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today, I am doing a Machine Learning internship with Acronis, a cyber security solutions firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have shared my story in a fast forward fashion to interviewers and new people I meet, I thought of detailing down why I made such a switch from Social Science to Data Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-should-i-do-with-my-degree&quot;&gt;What should I do with my degree?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my peers wanted to join the public service. But not me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t enjoy whatever I was studying at school. Coming from a science background in college, I was disturbed by the uncertainties in humanities subjects. The theoretical nature of these subjects also put me off. I wanted to see the practical aspect of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my second year, I got a GPA of 3.12. As I didn’t hit the GPA requirement for my scholarship, the school withdrew my scholarship. It was a deafening call. Though I could get average results, I couldn’t excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next semester, I took modules that I liked, including a finance one, and scored 3 As that term (compared to no As the previous term). I started seeing the joy in studying. It also dawned on me that I was more of a logical thinker - numbers and structures were very intuitive to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should I do now? I was lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recalled what I said as a 19-year-old at the interview room when I applied to my degree: &lt;em&gt;I wanted to learn about what’s happening around the world - the issues people face, and how we can solve them.&lt;/em&gt; I had a big dream to make an impact in people’s lives. But I haven’t found out how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that mission in mind, I sought to find the bus that would take me to my destination. There were many pathways I could take to reach my dreams. I could go into social service; I could join an international institution, like the World Bank. Yet, those paths didn’t particularly attract me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then explored various internships to find out what I liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;maybe-a-data-analyst&quot;&gt;Maybe a data analyst?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More often, internships tell us more about what we dislike than what we like. But this still gets us one step closer to where we want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a Bill Gates’ fan, I chanced upon his book recommendation, Factfulness, by the Rosling family. It opened my eyes to the world of data. I saw how data visualization could make an impactful story; I saw how powerful data can be - and how we were often make to mistakenly believe what’s happening around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could do something similar as a career: a data analyst working on social data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I was lucky to be exposed to machine learning during my summer internship with Aon. My supervisor offered to let me work on a machine learning project with my fellow intern. Since I wanted to learn as much as I could during internship, I went for the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to find interest in the world of technology. The community seemed really helpful. There were discussion forums, such as Stack Overflow, where people posts questions that they needed help with and the community would offer suggestions. Many people also blog about various machine learning problems and their codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming a data analyst seem like a viable alternative I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-not-a-data-scientist-instead&quot;&gt;Why not a data scientist instead?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to defy norms. While people progress gradually from a non-technical background, to a data analyst then a data scientist, I set my eyes on the latter. I shall become a data scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucky for me, I got to know two data scientists in my team at Aon. One came from a statistics background, and the other from economics. I was surprised. Little did I know that statistics was as closely linked to data science as programming was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I bounced off the idea of becoming a data analyst to the data scientists, I realised the myths I had about data science were wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth 1&lt;/strong&gt;: I will lose out to my computer science peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely not. Data science is at the intersection of programming, statistics and domain knowledge. Since I was good at mathematics, I could potentially excel in data science!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth 2&lt;/strong&gt;: I need to be a strong programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not exactly. While data scientists have been chided for their unintelligible codes, data scientists do not have to be strong programmers. A decent programming ability would get you by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made me attracted to data science. I was also more interested in the problems that data scientists tackle as compared to those by data analysts. Furthermore, it would be easier to go from a more technical role, like data scientist, to a less technical role, like data analyst. Thus, I decided to give data science a try.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m an incoming final-year Politics, Law and Economics (PLE) major student. Never have I thought of going into the tech sector before my university days. In fact, when I started learning Python 1.5 years ago, I told myself I am not going to touch it again. Fast forward to today, I am doing a Machine Learning internship with Acronis, a cyber security solutions firm. While I have shared my story in a fast forward fashion to interviewers and new people I meet, I thought of detailing down why I made such a switch from Social Science to Data Science. What should I do with my degree? Most of my peers wanted to join the public service. But not me. I didn’t enjoy whatever I was studying at school. Coming from a science background in college, I was disturbed by the uncertainties in humanities subjects. The theoretical nature of these subjects also put me off. I wanted to see the practical aspect of things. In my second year, I got a GPA of 3.12. As I didn’t hit the GPA requirement for my scholarship, the school withdrew my scholarship. It was a deafening call. Though I could get average results, I couldn’t excel. The next semester, I took modules that I liked, including a finance one, and scored 3 As that term (compared to no As the previous term). I started seeing the joy in studying. It also dawned on me that I was more of a logical thinker - numbers and structures were very intuitive to me. What should I do now? I was lost. I recalled what I said as a 19-year-old at the interview room when I applied to my degree: I wanted to learn about what’s happening around the world - the issues people face, and how we can solve them. I had a big dream to make an impact in people’s lives. But I haven’t found out how. With that mission in mind, I sought to find the bus that would take me to my destination. There were many pathways I could take to reach my dreams. I could go into social service; I could join an international institution, like the World Bank. Yet, those paths didn’t particularly attract me. I then explored various internships to find out what I liked. Maybe a data analyst? More often, internships tell us more about what we dislike than what we like. But this still gets us one step closer to where we want to be. Being a Bill Gates’ fan, I chanced upon his book recommendation, Factfulness, by the Rosling family. It opened my eyes to the world of data. I saw how data visualization could make an impactful story; I saw how powerful data can be - and how we were often make to mistakenly believe what’s happening around the world. I could do something similar as a career: a data analyst working on social data. At the same time, I was lucky to be exposed to machine learning during my summer internship with Aon. My supervisor offered to let me work on a machine learning project with my fellow intern. Since I wanted to learn as much as I could during internship, I went for the opportunity. I started to find interest in the world of technology. The community seemed really helpful. There were discussion forums, such as Stack Overflow, where people posts questions that they needed help with and the community would offer suggestions. Many people also blog about various machine learning problems and their codes. Becoming a data analyst seem like a viable alternative I thought. Why not a data scientist instead? I love to defy norms. While people progress gradually from a non-technical background, to a data analyst then a data scientist, I set my eyes on the latter. I shall become a data scientist. Lucky for me, I got to know two data scientists in my team at Aon. One came from a statistics background, and the other from economics. I was surprised. Little did I know that statistics was as closely linked to data science as programming was. As I bounced off the idea of becoming a data analyst to the data scientists, I realised the myths I had about data science were wrong. Myth 1: I will lose out to my computer science peers. Absolutely not. Data science is at the intersection of programming, statistics and domain knowledge. Since I was good at mathematics, I could potentially excel in data science! Myth 2: I need to be a strong programmer. Not exactly. While data scientists have been chided for their unintelligible codes, data scientists do not have to be strong programmers. A decent programming ability would get you by. This made me attracted to data science. I was also more interested in the problems that data scientists tackle as compared to those by data analysts. Furthermore, it would be easier to go from a more technical role, like data scientist, to a less technical role, like data analyst. Thus, I decided to give data science a try.</summary></entry></feed>